# Joseph F. Ghanimah

jfghanimah@gmail.com • (630) 670-7606 www.josephghanimah.com

#### **SUMMARY**

Exceptionally adaptable Computer Engineering major currently attending the University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign with minors in Mathematical Statistics and Data Science. Strong critical and lateral thinking skills with 2+ years of relevant experience with full stack application development and predictive analytics.

#### **EDUCATION**

#### University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign

**Urbana-Champaign, IL** *August 2018 - May 2022* 

Bachelor of Science, Computer Engineering

• Minors: Mathematical Statistics, Data Science

- Awards & Honors: President's Award Program Honors Student, College of Engineering James Scholar
- Activities: Illini Esports Manager & Headcoach

## **EXPERIENCE**

College CoD League Wood Dale, IL

Full-Stack Software Engineer (www.collegecod.com)

June 2018 - Present

- Manage DigitalOcean linux web server with Nginx and Gunicorn
- Design, deploy, and maintain website, using Python (Django), JS, CSS, and HTML
- Identify problems uncovered by testing or customer feedback, and correct problems or refer problems to appropriate personnel for correction
- Develop a PostgreSQL database infrastructure that supports thousands of data entries to enable in-depth player stat tracking
- Document technical factors such as server load, bandwidth, database performance and browser and device types
- Track SEO and web analytics to present with internal development and design teams

G3 Circuit L.L.C. Urbana-Champaign, IL

Founder & Lead Developer

August 2018 - September 2019

- Lead a team of 20+, distributing company's limited resources to ensure goal of expanding competitive play to a wider audience
- Organized 300+ competitors in various matches and tournaments for league season
- Deployed a serverless web application on Google Cloud Platform (GCP) to manage teams and players using Python (Flask), MySQL, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript

# O'Hare Freight USA Inc.

Bensenville, IL

Night Shift Security Guard

May 2017 - August 2018

- Delivered written and verbal reports of over-night activities and irregularities of industrial premises such as property damage, theft, presence of unauthorized persons, or unusual occurrences
- Inspected and adjusted security systems and equipment to ensure operations use and to detect evidence of tampering

### **ADDITIONAL SKILLS**

- Project experience with machine learning, cloud computing, automation, and data visualization
- Proficient in Python (Django, Flask, TensorFlow, NumPy)
- Additional familiarity with C++, C#, SQL, Javascript, HTML, and CSS
- Involvement with collaborating in small and large team environments using applications like Trello, Slack, Github, and Discord
- Competent with video, photo, and audio editing tools